<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Baguio>
    <landmarks>
        <landmark>
            <name>Burnham Park</name>
            <image>./images/landmark1.jpg</image>
            <location>Abad Santos Drive, Baguio, Luzon 2600 Philippines</location>
            <desc>The 'mother of all parks' in Baguio city, the summer capital of the Philippines, is a 32.84-hectare park designed by, and named after, American architect and urban planner Daniel Hudson Burnham, who also designed the original plan for Baguio City as well as Dewey Boulevard (now Roxas Boulevard) in Manila. The park has 12 main areas, the most popular of which are the Burnham Lagoon, a man-made lake with rowboats for hire; a children's playground; a skating rink; the Rose Garden and the Picnic Grove.</desc>
            <history>Burnham Park is named after Daniel Burnham, an American architect who was the city planner for Baguio. He designed the park and the original plans for the city simultaneously, and construction began around 1904. Burnham Park covers the only large expanse of level ground within hilly surroundings. The modern park, although smaller than the original park due to urban development, retains much of its original design and layout. The park played an important role when it served as a place of refuge for the people of Baguio following a devastating earthquake in 1990.</history>
        </landmark>
        <landmark>
            <name>Mines View Park</name>
            <image>./images/landmark2.jpg</image>
            <location>Outlook Drive, Baguio, Luzon 2600 Philippines</location>
            <desc>Mines View Park is an overlook park on the northeastern outskirts of Baguio in the Philippines. It is five kilometers away from the Heart of Baguio, passing through the Botanical Garden, the Mansion House, Wright Park, and the Pacdal Circle.Located on a land promontory 4 km from downtown Baguio, the park overlooks the mining town of Itogon, particularly the abandoned gold and copper mines of the Benguet Corporation, and offers a glimpse of the Amburayan Valley. The observation deck is situated below a winding stone-covered stairway close to the parking area.</desc>
            <history>During the early seventies, local children used to wait far below the viewing deck to catch coins being thrown down by tourists using makeshift sticks with baskets on top.  However, due to the extremities of the location, accidents did occur and the local government finally forbade the practice.  A memoriam is erected on one side of the cliff to commemorate those children that lost their lives in making a living in the area.</history>
        </landmark>
        <landmark>
            <name>The Mansion</name>
            <image>./images/landmark3.jpg</image>
            <location>Leonard Wood Road, Baguio, Luzon 2600 Philippines</location>
            <desc>The Mansion is the official summer residence of the President of the Philippines. It is located on the eastern part of the city along C.P. Romulo Drive (formerly a part of Leonard Wood Road) and right across from Wright Park. Older than the city itself, the Mansion is easily one of the most visited and photographed landmarks of Baguio. Inside the Mansion is a mini museum housing memorabilia and works of art collected over its years of occupancy by the former presidents. Within the compound and adjacent to the Mansion is a two-story building which serves as the official residence of the Philippine President in Baguio City and nearby is a small amphitheater. A contingent of Philippine marines maintains the security of this large compound and you will see a some of them manning the guardhouse at the vicinity of the gate.</desc>
            <history>Formerly called the Mansion House, this stately building was built in 1908 as summer homes for U.S. Governor-generals who were the American administrators for the Philippines and was destroyed in 1945 during the battle for the liberation of the Philippines. The Philippine government later rebuilt and improved the structure in 1947 and since then it has been used by various Philippine presidents whenever they come up to Baguio City for their official visits and engagements. The Mansion once served as the seat of the Second Session of Economic Commission of Asia and the Far East in 1947. It has also been the site of first meeting of the South East Asia Union which was popularly known as the Baguio Conference of 1950, conceived and convened by Philippine President Elpidio Quirino.</history>
        </landmark>
        <landmark>
            <name>Lion's Head</name>
            <image>./images/landmark4.jpg</image>
            <location>Kennon Road, Camp 6; near the Baguio-Tuba boundary, Benguet, Philippines</location>
            <desc>Found along Kennon Road in the outskirts of Baguio City in Benguet,  is a 40-foot man-made and painted gigantic rock that resembles a lion's head. It was commissioned by the Lions Club of Baguio City. So what's behind the giant lion's head sculpture? The story goes that years ago when tourists started to flock to Baguio City by means of Kennon Road, they used a large rock, which is naturally shaped like a lion, as a landmark that they are near Baguio City. Due to its popularity, the city government decided to "remodel" the large rock so that it would literally be known as the Lion's Head.</desc>            
            <history>The Lion's Head was conceived by the Lions of Baguio in the late 1960's, and was formally unveiled to the public in 1972, with PDG Luis Lardizabal, then District Governor Robert John Webber and then-President Pedro Z. Claravall spearheading the project.  The 40-foot sculpture was carved out of natural limestone by Cordilleran artist Reynaldo Lopez Nanyac. The original Lion's Head was financed partly through generous donations by Baguio Lions Club members and from proceeds generated by the recently-concluded State Convention in Baguio City.</history>
        </landmark>
        <landmark>
            <name>Philippine Military Academy</name>
            <image>./images/landmark5.jpg</image>
            <location>9J69+9Q3, Baguio, 2600 Benguet Philippines</location>
            <desc>The Philippine Military Academy also referred to by its acronym PMA is the premier military academy for Filipinos aspiring for a commission as a military officer of the Armed Forces of the Philippines. It was established on December 21, 1936, by the virtue of National Defense Act of 1935.</desc>
            <history>The Philippine Military Academy began on October 25, 1898 with the establishment of the Academia Militar in Malolos, Bulacan by virtue of a decree issued by the first president of the young Philippine Republic, General Emilio Aguinaldo. Graduates were awarded regular commission in the armed forces. Its existence was short-lived, barely four months old, up to 20 January 1899, when hostilities between the Americans and Filipinos erupted. While the Philippines was under American colonial rule, an officer's school of the Philippine Constabulary was established at the Walled City of Intramuros in Manila on February 17, 1905. It relocated three years later to Baguio City, initially at Camp Henry T. Allen, and subsequently at Teacher's Camp.</history>
        </landmark>
    </landmarks>

    <cultures>

    </cultures>

    <foods>

    </foods>

    <festivals>

    </festivals>

    <mountains>

    </mountains>

    <churches>

    </churches>
</Baguio>