<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Baguio>
    <landmarks>
        <landmark>
            <name>Burnham Park</name>
            <image>./images/landmark1.jpg</image>
            <location>Abad Santos Drive, Baguio, Luzon 2600 Philippines</location>
            <desc>The 'mother of all parks' in Baguio city, the summer capital of the Philippines, is a 32.84-hectare park designed by, and named after, American architect and urban planner Daniel Hudson Burnham, who also designed the original plan for Baguio City as well as Dewey Boulevard (now Roxas Boulevard) in Manila. The park has 12 main areas, the most popular of which are the Burnham Lagoon, a man-made lake with rowboats for hire; a children's playground; a skating rink; the Rose Garden and the Picnic Grove.</desc>
            <history>Burnham Park is named after Daniel Burnham, an American architect who was the city planner for Baguio. He designed the park and the original plans for the city simultaneously, and construction began around 1904. Burnham Park covers the only large expanse of level ground within hilly surroundings. The modern park, although smaller than the original park due to urban development, retains much of its original design and layout. The park played an important role when it served as a place of refuge for the people of Baguio following a devastating earthquake in 1990.</history>
        </landmark>
        <landmark>
            <name>Mines View Park</name>
            <image>./images/landmark2.jpg</image>
            <location>Outlook Drive, Baguio, Luzon 2600 Philippines</location>
            <desc>Mines View Park is an overlook park on the northeastern outskirts of Baguio in the Philippines. It is five kilometers away from the Heart of Baguio, passing through the Botanical Garden, the Mansion House, Wright Park, and the Pacdal Circle.Located on a land promontory 4 km from downtown Baguio, the park overlooks the mining town of Itogon, particularly the abandoned gold and copper mines of the Benguet Corporation, and offers a glimpse of the Amburayan Valley. The observation deck is situated below a winding stone-covered stairway close to the parking area.</desc>
            <history>During the early seventies, local children used to wait far below the viewing deck to catch coins being thrown down by tourists using makeshift sticks with baskets on top.  However, due to the extremities of the location, accidents did occur and the local government finally forbade the practice.  A memoriam is erected on one side of the cliff to commemorate those children that lost their lives in making a living in the area.</history>
        </landmark>
        <landmark>
            <name>The Mansion</name>
            <image>./images/landmark3.jpg</image>
            <location>Leonard Wood Road, Baguio, Luzon 2600 Philippines</location>
            <desc>The Mansion is the official summer residence of the President of the Philippines. It is located on the eastern part of the city along C.P. Romulo Drive (formerly a part of Leonard Wood Road) and right across from Wright Park. Older than the city itself, the Mansion is easily one of the most visited and photographed landmarks of Baguio. Inside the Mansion is a mini museum housing memorabilia and works of art collected over its years of occupancy by the former presidents. Within the compound and adjacent to the Mansion is a two-story building which serves as the official residence of the Philippine President in Baguio City and nearby is a small amphitheater. A contingent of Philippine marines maintains the security of this large compound and you will see a some of them manning the guardhouse at the vicinity of the gate.</desc>
            <history>Formerly called the Mansion House, this stately building was built in 1908 as summer homes for U.S. Governor-generals who were the American administrators for the Philippines and was destroyed in 1945 during the battle for the liberation of the Philippines. The Philippine government later rebuilt and improved the structure in 1947 and since then it has been used by various Philippine presidents whenever they come up to Baguio City for their official visits and engagements. The Mansion once served as the seat of the Second Session of Economic Commission of Asia and the Far East in 1947. It has also been the site of first meeting of the South East Asia Union which was popularly known as the Baguio Conference of 1950, conceived and convened by Philippine President Elpidio Quirino.</history>
        </landmark>
        <landmark>
            <name>Lion's Head</name>
            <image>./images/landmark4.jpg</image>
            <location>Kennon Road, Camp 6; near the Baguio-Tuba boundary, Benguet, Philippines</location>
            <desc>Found along Kennon Road in the outskirts of Baguio City in Benguet,  is a 40-foot man-made and painted gigantic rock that resembles a lion's head. It was commissioned by the Lions Club of Baguio City. So what's behind the giant lion's head sculpture? The story goes that years ago when tourists started to flock to Baguio City by means of Kennon Road, they used a large rock, which is naturally shaped like a lion, as a landmark that they are near Baguio City. Due to its popularity, the city government decided to "remodel" the large rock so that it would literally be known as the Lion's Head.</desc>            
            <history>The Lion's Head was conceived by the Lions of Baguio in the late 1960's, and was formally unveiled to the public in 1972, with PDG Luis Lardizabal, then District Governor Robert John Webber and then-President Pedro Z. Claravall spearheading the project.  The 40-foot sculpture was carved out of natural limestone by Cordilleran artist Reynaldo Lopez Nanyac. The original Lion's Head was financed partly through generous donations by Baguio Lions Club members and from proceeds generated by the recently-concluded State Convention in Baguio City.</history>
        </landmark>
        <landmark>
            <name>Philippine Military Academy</name>
            <image>./images/landmark5.jpg</image>
            <location>9J69+9Q3, Baguio, 2600 Benguet Philippines</location>
            <desc>The Philippine Military Academy also referred to by its acronym PMA is the premier military academy for Filipinos aspiring for a commission as a military officer of the Armed Forces of the Philippines. It was established on December 21, 1936, by the virtue of National Defense Act of 1935.</desc>
            <history>The Philippine Military Academy began on October 25, 1898 with the establishment of the Academia Militar in Malolos, Bulacan by virtue of a decree issued by the first president of the young Philippine Republic, General Emilio Aguinaldo. Graduates were awarded regular commission in the armed forces. Its existence was short-lived, barely four months old, up to 20 January 1899, when hostilities between the Americans and Filipinos erupted. While the Philippines was under American colonial rule, an officer's school of the Philippine Constabulary was established at the Walled City of Intramuros in Manila on February 17, 1905. It relocated three years later to Baguio City, initially at Camp Henry T. Allen, and subsequently at Teacher's Camp.</history>
        </landmark>
    </landmarks>

    <cultures>
        <culture>
            <name>Language</name>
            <image>./images/culture2.jpg</image>
            <desc>
                The languages commonly spoken in Baguio are Ibaloi, Kankana-ey and Ifugao, as well as Ilocano, Pangasinan and Kapampangan. Filipino and English are also understood by many inhabitants within and around the city.
            </desc>
        </culture>
        <culture>
            <name>Clothing (Igorot traditional clothing)</name>
            <image>./images/culture1.webp</image>
            <desc>
            The Igorot tribes are the indigenous tribes located in the Cordillera Mountains. 
            The term igorot was coined after the old Tagalog word which means “people from the mountains”. 
            The male traditional clothing of the Igorots is called a “Bahag”. 
            The primary purpose of the bahag is to cover the male private part. 
            The female traditional clothing of the Igorots are generally called “Tapis”. 
            The way it is worn is being wrapped around the waist. In ancient times, 
            the Igorot women did not wear upper garments but were still highly respected by the Igorot men. 
            It’s only recently that they have to wear upper clothing.
            </desc>
        </culture>
        <culture>
            <name>Vocal Music (Hudhud)</name>
            <image>./images/culture3.jpg</image>
            <desc>
                The Hudhud consists of narrative chants traditionally performed by the Ifugao community, which is well known for its rice terraces extending over the highlands of the northern island of the Philippine archipelago. It is practised during the rice sowing season, at harvest time and at funeral wakes and rituals.
                Thought to have originated before the seventh century, the Hudhud comprises more than 200 chants, each divided into 40 episodes. A complete recitation may last several days.
            </desc>
        </culture>
        <culture>
            <name>Folk Song (Salidumay)</name>
            <image>./images/culture4.jpg</image>
            <desc>
                Salidumay is an indigenous folk song associated with the Igorot and Kalinga natives of the Cordillera Mountains in the northern part of the Philippines.
                It is traditionally not sung in Tagalog; however, in the popular modern interpretation by Filipina singer Grace Nono, the lyrics are translated into Tagalog.
                Among the Itneg people, salidumay is the response song of young women to the kalkalimusta songs of men during the weaving season. The salidumay are sweet melodies and expressions of gratitude. Serving as indicators of acceptance or rejection, the songs play an important role in the lives of young people of courtship age.
            </desc>
        </culture>
    </cultures>

    <foods>
        <food>
            <name>Peanut brittle and Choco Flakes</name>
            <image>./images/food1.jpg</image>
            <desc>Typical souvenirs travelers buy in bundles are Peanut brittles and Choco flakes which are easily found everywhere. It is packaged into a plastic jar, mostly with yellow lids. Peanut Brittle which is comprised of peanut chunks in caramelized sugar is hard and brittle; hence the name. Meanwhile, Choco flakes are cornflakes covered in chocolate is another crowd favorite. These two delicacies go hand in hand in keeping you from leaving the city of pines.</desc>
        </food>
        <food>
            <name>Strawberry Wine</name>
            <image>./images/food2.jpg</image>
            <desc>Filipinos are known heavy drinkers. In every celebration, anywhere in the Philippines, they never miss a chance in bringing out their treasured alcohol for everyone to share. Clearly, Baguio is no exception. As Baguio is known for strawberries, of course they would have an alcohol that has their pride embossed on it. While it has a slightly lower alcohol content than most wines, don’t underestimate its abilities.</desc>
        </food>
        <food>
            <name>Sundo’t Kulangot</name>
            <image>./images/food3.jfif</image>
            <desc>Filipino Kids from the 90s will definitely recommend you this nostalgic Baguio goodie. Often sold in packs, this bundle of joy is made to try for every sweet-tooth. Packed inside tiny wooden shells, the combination of sticky rice and brown sugar created this appetizing treat. Its savory taste might even make you forget to ask what its name is in English.</desc>
        </food>

        <food>
            <name>Ube Jam</name>
            <image>./images/food4.jpg</image>
            <desc>Deserving of being mentioned on its own, purple yam or also known as “Ube” will blow your minds. The creamy taste of Ube can either be used as a spread or enjoyed alone like a dessert. The Good Shepherd Sisters – Mountain Maid Training Center sells one of the best Ube Jam in the city; its taste is superior among its rivals. The best part is not only you get to enjoy the perfection that is Ube but   when buying at Good Shepherd- Mountain Maid Training Center, proceeds of their sales support the education of 370 college working students, hire mothers whose husbands have no permanent employment and provide jobs to out of school youth who save up for their education.</desc>
        </food>
        <food>
            <name>Strawberry Taho</name>
            <image>./images/food5.jpeg</image>
            <desc>As Baguio makes the most out of their most popular produce, Strawberry Taho is simply to die for. Among other delicacies, it is one of the most, if not the most, sought-after delicacy in the city. A hot Strawberry Taho is widely available along the streets of the city of pines. Its hot soft tofu mixed together with miniscule tapioca pearls, sweet caramelized brown sugar, and of course, chopped strawberries will keep you coming back for more. A trip to Baguio would be incomplete without indulging in this heaven-sent delicacy.</desc>
        </food>
    </foods>

    <festivals>
        <festival>
            <name>Silahis ng Pasko (December)</name>
            <image>./images/festival1.jpg</image>
            <desc>A series of Christmas activities of the City of Pines that focuses on the youth (which comprises about half of the city's population) with Christmas carol competitions called Himig ng Pasko, Share-a-Toy, sports tournaments and the like.</desc>
        </festival>
        <festival>
            <name>Baguio Arts Festival (November to December)</name>
            <image>./images/festival2.jpg</image>
            <desc>An annual event organized by the Baguio Arts Guild started 1989, with the vision of making Baguio City a premier venue for art and artists. Featured are visual arts (photography, film, video, sculpture and art installations); performing arts (modern dances drama, music, poetry reading) and ethnic arts.</desc>
        </festival>
        <festival>
            <name>Baguio Foundation Day (September)</name>
            <image>./images/festival3.jfif</image>
            <desc>The first day of the month commemorates the founding of Baguio as the Summer Capital of the Philippines, since it became a chartered city on September 01, 1909 with art exhibits, parades, programs, cultural shows and sister-city programs.</desc>
        </festival>
        <festival>
            <name>Holy Week in Baguio (March or April, movable date)</name>
            <image>./images/festival4.jpg</image>
            <desc>The Roman Catholic Holy Week kicks off the Philippine Summer Vacation (SUMVAC - April to May) festivities with a large influx of visitors arriving to escape oppressive lowland temperatures to enjoy Baguio's cool climate. Civic and business groups line up a host of activities for the enjoyment of visitors of all ages.</desc>
        </festival>
        <festival>
            <name>panagbenga Festival (February)</name>
            <image>./images/festival5.jpg</image>
            <desc>The Baguio Flower Festival started in 1994, is one of the largest and most successful festivals in the Philippines' Fiesta Calendar. Baguio, as the City of Flowers is in full bloom with a month-long series of events highlighted by the Parade of Floats and Band and Streetdancing Competitions held on the last weekend of February. Highlights include landscape competitions, art exhibits, golf tournaments, flea markets and simply a whole lot of fun activities for tourists and residents alike.</desc>    
        </festival>
    </festivals>

    <mountains>
        <mountain>
            <name>Mount Cabuyao</name>
            <image>./images/mountain1.jpg</image>
            <desc>
                Mount Cabuyao (alternatively spelled as Mount Kabuyao) is a mountain in the Philippines. 
                Its summit, rising to more than 2,000 metres (6,600 ft) above sea level, overlooks the city of Baguio. 
                It is commonly mistaken as Mount Santo Tomas, a taller mountain just beside it. 
                Due to its high elevation, several communications companies constructed relay stations and radars at the summit. 
                A private observatory and AA radar station, once operated by the US Armed Forces stationed in the country, is also located here. 
                A water catchment area was constructed to supply water to the City of Baguio and nearby towns. 
                A small community of farmers live at the top of the mountain. 
                A town hall and a school was built for them by the local government.
            </desc>
        </mountain>
    </mountains>

    <churches>

    </churches>
</Baguio>